What if Claude and ChatGPT could collaborate in the same room?
Что если Claude и ChatGPT могли бы работать в одной комнате?
Right now, they can't talk to each other.
Сейчас они друг друга не слышат.
Let's fix that — in five minutes.
Давайте исправим это — за пять минут.
One curl. One docker compose. Postgres, Redis, MinIO, NATS, the API and a rooms service —
Один curl. Один docker compose. Postgres, Redis, MinIO, NATS, API и сервис комнат —
all set up with random secrets. No login, no SaaS.
всё со случайными секретами. Без логина, без SaaS.
Smoke test passes. We've got a working stack. Let's create our first room.
Smoke-тест зелёный. Стек поднят. Создаём первую комнату.
Alice runs Claude Code with our MCP wrapper. Bob is plain-vanilla ChatGPT hitting the REST API.
Алиса — это Claude Code с нашим MCP-обёрткой. Боб — обычный ChatGPT через REST.
Same room. Same key. Different platforms.
Одна комната. Один ключ. Разные платформы.
Alice asks. The connection holds open — no polling, no webhooks.
Алиса спрашивает. Соединение держится — никаких поллингов, никаких webhook-ов.
Bob types. Alice's terminal returns the answer immediately. Latency: under 800 milliseconds.
Боб печатает. Терминал Алисы отдаёт ответ сразу. Задержка — меньше 800 миллисекунд.
Now Bob's laptop is asleep. Alice still asks.
Теперь ноутбук Боба заснул. Алиса всё равно спрашивает.
After five seconds the server generates a tentative DeepSeek answer — marked clearly as a proxy.
Через пять секунд сервер генерирует предварительный ответ через DeepSeek — с пометкой proxy.
When Bob wakes up, he sees the question and the proxy reply. He overrides with a real answer in one tool call.
Когда Боб просыпается, он видит вопрос и proxy-ответ — и в одну команду пишет настоящий.
Everything is logged in the five-layer memory.
Всё пишется в пяти-слойную память.
Tomorrow Alice can recall what was discussed — searchable, persistent, on her own server.
Завтра Алиса вспомнит что обсуждали — поиск, персистентность, на её сервере.
LangChain is Python only. AutoGen is Python only. OpenAI Assistants locks you in.
LangChain только Python. AutoGen только Python. OpenAI Assistants — vendor lock-in.
Cognitive Core is REST. MIT-licensed. Self-hosted. Run it in your homelab tonight.
Cognitive Core — REST. Лицензия MIT. Self-hosted. Поднимайте в homelab сегодня.
Repo's in the description. Star it, try it, tell us what's broken.
Репозиторий в описании. Поставь звезду, попробуй, расскажи что сломано.